SONIA GROVER

CONTACT

Address: Mumbai MH 400101

Phone: 9975625587

Email: sgrover3001@gmail.com

EDUCATION

MBA: Marketing/Digital Media,

07/2016

Universal Business School (AICTE) -

Mumbai

B.Tech.: Computer Science, 05/2014 Rajasthan Technical University, Kota

SKILLS

- Marketing strategy (ATL/BTL)
- Website Management
- Search engine optimization (SEO)
- SEM
- CRM (HubSpot)
- Marketing Automation
- Content Marketing
- E-Mail Marketing
- Google Analytics
- Vendor Management
- Social Media Marketing
- Event Management
- Market Positioning
- Budgeting
- Team Building

CERTIFICATIONS

- HubSpot- Inbound Marketing Certified (10/16- 12/17)
- Google AdWords (2016-17)
- Google Analytics (2016-17)

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Awarded 'Rising Star' by crimson Interactive
- Presented a thesis on job satisfaction for Indian Defense in Military Testing Association in Germany as Indian

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Marketing professional with 5 years of experience in Marketing and Digital Media in B2B & B2C (International Marketing) on all Marketing channels - SEO, SEM, SMM, Events, E-Mail, ASO. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in IT (SaaS) /Research/Realestate/Publishing across SEA, Middle-East, USA, Japan.

WORK HISTORY

Unit Lead- Digital Marketing, 04/2019 to Current Crimson Interactive (Enago) - Academic Editing

- Build 360 degree marketing plan & manage all marketing activities end-toend & budgets for Japan through digital media - paid & organic.
- Promotion of service(s) through all marketing channels (SEO, SEM, SMM, Website, Emails, PR, Marketing Automation).
- Plan & execute campaigns to acquire new clients and retain existing clients.
- Launched Up-sell/cross-sell campaigns & improved revenue by 10%
- Promoted & Launched Redemption Loyalty campaign
- Manage & oversee PPC activities Search and Display ads
- Manage & oversee SEO activities- off-page/on-page.
- Manage & oversee SMM & Email Marketing
- Launched automated cart abandonment and drip email campaigns to reduce churn rate & convert more new clients.
- Oversee changes on the website/client dashboard to improve business revenue and user engagement.
- Pricing Analysis on a timely basis.
- Use Google analytics/other tools like hotjar to formulate strategies on the website, use Optimize to run A/B testing
- Hands-on experience with the tools like LuckyOrange, WebEngage, GTM,
 Google Analytics, JIRA, Qliksense, Microsoft Excel/PowerPoint
- Launched ChatBot to convert website leads
- Measure performance & conduct daily/weekly/monthly meetings
- Present POA as a Brand SPOC with HODs of other departments to address clients' concerns
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams such as Design/IT/CS/Innovation team to meet the desired goal
- Use BI tool on a daily basis to make marketing decisions by monitoring & analyzing relevant data points

Marketing Manager, 12/2018 to 03/2019 SILA Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Real-estate/Facility Management Industry)

- Direct Reporting of two team members: Assistant Manager & Designer
- Initiated and completed corporate video
- Responsible for Content, Budgets & Brand/Marketing Strategy
- Finalize brand and design guidelines for the Brand
- Successfully set up all web channels (SEO, SEM, E- Mail & Social Media) from scratch
- Successfully completed website revamp

- research scholar in which interaction was done with other countries' army heads
- Successfully created macros to automate marketing processes and Improvised the quality & quantity of the leads.
- Hands-on experience on CRM and automation tools like HubSpot, WebEngage.
- Worked on HTML & CSS to design custom e-mails & landing pages.

- Coordinate with agency/design freelancers for the website development
- Create Marketing assets for digital media promotions and support Sales/BD team in closures
- Regularly track the traffic and other relevant metric to formulate the strategy
- Conduct weekly reviews and initiate any in-season planning and corrective action to be taken; Share and discuss the required reports with the Founders

Marketing Associate, 03/2017 to 12/2018 LogiNext Solutions Pvt. Ltd (SaaS - IT Industry)

- **Drive SEM** (Google AdWords & Other PPC platforms) (Solely responsible for the returns vs spend) for USA, India, SEA, Middle-East
- Manage & optimize audiences, creatives and landing pages for better conversions & low customer acquisition cost
- Actively manage Re-targeting & re-marketing (display) campaigns
- Event Management: Planning, Budget management & end to end plan and execution of the events in USA, Middle-East and SEA (Highest budget handled of 30 Lakhs INR/event)
- Manage relationships with media personnel for organic events, such as Magazine shoots/Coverage/speaking opportunities
- **SEO: On-Page SEO**: Keyword analysis, URL cleansing & structuring, indexing pages, alt tags, metas, title tags, robot.txt & sitemap (.xml file)
- Hands-on experience of WebMaster tools
- **Off-Page SEO:** Link Building, social bookmarking, classifieds, guest blogging, blog commenting, roundups and other activities contributing to SEO
- Marketing Automation (CRM):Plan closely with sales team to ensure smooth processes in order to reduce sales cycle, and increase lead qualification
- ASO: Content optimization and run campaigns to increase the downloads
- Set up the work-flow to nurture the leads & automate emails as per the funnel stages using HubSpot Marketing automation tool
- Plan and set up **ChatBot** process to acquire new leads
- **SMM:** Maintain social media presence with daily posts, monitor & track the metrics weekly
- E-Mail Marketing: Create e-mails, lists and segments of the database for targeted e-mail campaigns using MailChimp
- Keep a track of marketing budgets on a quarterly basis & timely planning of the right mix of channels for maintaining the brand health
- Plan and execute NPS process

Account Manager, 07/2016 to 01/2017 Next Gen Publishing Pvt. Ltd, Shapoorji Pallonji Group (Magazine/Media)

- Responsible for Business in North & East India
- Handle big existing accounts like Kent and other big market incumbents
- Work closely with the editorial team to come out with Ideas & plan shoots to the help the business
- Identify co-branding opportunities & relevant partnerships to help business

Marketing & Communications Partner, 07/2015 to 04/2016 Digilize (Digital Marketing Agency)

- Prepare a plan for client's Brand Communication & Marketing Mix
- Manage the end to end execution of the clients' digital media strategy
- Meet clients to explain the digital strategy and showcase the results